<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sterling Consulting</title>
    <description>Marketing and Project Management Consultants</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 14:39:11 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 14:39:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Developed &amp;amp; Launched Business Credit Card</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regional Bank wanted to offer a business credit card to its clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sterling provided a top flight product manager to work the project from inception to launch.  Multiple stakeholders were involved and vendors. The product manager coordinated every detail with skill and precision leading the not only the successful launch of the bank’s first business card, but also the subsequent launch of a consumer card.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2013/01/01/financial-cs-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2013/01/01/financial-cs-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Planning &amp;amp; Facilitation of First Green Summit for National Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Bank Seeks Innovative Ways to Make Their Consumer Banking Products Green&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sterling facilitated the first green summit with over 50 of the bank’s product owners. Eight projects were outlined for implementation during 2011/12.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2011/01/01/financial-cs-5.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2011/01/01/financial-cs-5.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction of SalesForce.com for Community Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client, a regional retail and business bank was faced with the challenge of selling business clients services with outdated tools and technology making it difficult for the bankers to remain informed and competitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sterling conducted an inventory of all current sales, sales support, marketing and training materials used by three divisions at the bank. This included all print and online materials. Assessed the materials to determine what materials needed to be updated and/or developed to support business prospecting and sales in the three most profitable divisions of the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surveyed key stake holders, assessed findings and provided recommendations to senior management. We identified four phases for constructing and deploying new content. We recommended parallel efforts to support deployment including training, infrastructure upgrades and sales portal technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provided copy writers and one project manager to deliver. Additionally, we conducted senior management strategy sessions to outline a comprehensive sales tool kit to lay the foundation for a more robust sales foundation with the infrastructure to support the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2010/01/01/financial-4.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2010/01/01/financial-4.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>California Utility Manages Rebates</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Client needed technology to track, manage, and report customer rebates received from purchasing energy efficient products. Our client was faced with the challenge of tracking rebates provided to consumers who purchase products that include a rebate. An antiquated system was in place which required either an upgrade, modification or replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sterling provided a business requirements analyst to gather comprehensive requirements. The requirements were used to develop an RFP. A Sterling Business PM also led the effort to keep the project on track and to manage and resolve the issues and risks. The client made the decision to band aid the existing system until a more robust platform and service provider could be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2008/01/01/energy-cs-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2008/01/01/energy-cs-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>National Health Care Provider Seeks EDS Migration Assistance</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customer needed to coordinate over 40 Projects to meet aggressive migration to EDS platform. Our client was facing an uphill battle tracking and monitoring multiple projects and their numerous interdependencies. They were at risk and needed to ensure a successful staging to handle a new EDS migration to track claim processing from beginning to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sterling provided a highly skilled project manager to build a master plan and to manage and mitigate the risks associated with the high number of inter-dependencies across the IT and business projects.
The project was delivered on time and serious risks were avoided due to the collaborative leadership skills of the PM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2007/01/01/health-cs-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2007/01/01/health-cs-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Created Sales Training Basics Curriculum for National Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping a consumer oriented bank actively acquire small business clients. Our client, a National Retail bank, offered an unsecured line of credit (LOC) to 30 community banks under the community bank’s brand to boost small business banking penetration. But most bankers in the community banks were not accustomed to serving the small business segment, and the added challenge of a new product introduction created hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conducted an assessment of the success of a small business lending product in New England using a questionnaire and telephone interviews. The results demonstrated that the bankers were challenged in developing small business banking relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our consultants worked to migrate these smaller banks to a culture of seeking and serving small business relationships, including a refresher course on “Sales Basics” to provide bankers with more confidence and knowledge in their communications skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provided specific recommendations unique to each bank to revisit their hiring practices to actively hire sales oriented bankers, to reinvest in training and retraining, and to enhance or to develop marketing tools to attract and maintain small business customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2006/01/01/financial-cs-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2006/01/01/financial-cs-3.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Launched IT Platform for Online Brokerage Division of a National Bank</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online banking for business needed significant upgrade. This national retail bank was on the fast track to launch enhanced features to attract additional small business clients and meet the needs of current customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sterling Consultants managed the project team and developers across multiple IT divisions and technology platforms to develop project plan, created and managed issues and issue resolution, constructed functional specifications, walkthroughs, user acceptance testing, QA, change management queue, regression testing, launch and post launch upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with business partners, consultants helped to develop, test and launch new features including: online brokerage, access to Quicken and Money; Account Activity and Transfer Services; On Line Statements, and Email Alerts. All features were launched on time and 10% under budget; additionally, streamlining of developers’ roles and responsibilities eliminated redundancies in development efforts for estimated annual savings of $1.5M.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2005/01/01/financial-cs-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2005/01/01/financial-cs-2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Broker Dealer Launches New Product &amp;amp; New Market with PM Leadership</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to increase trades and new assets among active traders in the Asia Pacific segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed a bundled product offering to stimulate trades among active traders in the Asia Pacific segment. We did so by analyzing trading statistics of the market segment and conducting focus groups with a sampling of active traders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed a bundled product offering to stimulate trades among active traders in the Asia Pacific segment. We did so by analyzing trading statistics of the market segment and conducting focus groups with a sampling of active traders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed the development of the product in concert with the technology partner and coordinated the marketing and advertising campaign to promote growth in sales for a sample of customers in a “beta” test environment for six months. The product stimulated increased trading activity by 30% in the segment after going live in the first six months. Client decided to launch nationally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2003/01/01/broker-dealer-cs-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/2003/01/01/broker-dealer-cs-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Historic Online Trading Launched in San Francisco</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenge&quot;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Founder of one of the nation’s most innovative financial advisory firms had a vision: to offer the common man the opportunity to buy and sell equities online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solution-delivered&quot;&gt;Solution Delivered&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sterling provided two Senior Business Analysts to write the business requirements for the creation and launch of Schwab.com. The rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1995 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/1995/01/01/broker-dealer-cs-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/casestudies/case%20studies/1995/01/01/broker-dealer-cs-2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>casestudies</category>
        
        <category>Case Studies</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
